字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
木浅
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
showeryhe
翻译
小酸奶!
累  冬麟
翻译
桃小兔吃冰棒
静妹粒
时间轴
chance-coco  兜兜兜爹  抑郁郁
电脑狂人
第三季
第九集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
阿马多·古德·吉尔森风险投资
阿马多·古德·吉尔森·埃默森
卡梅伦
东京 至 拉斯维加斯
到达时间 11月14日 下午3点13分
乔
微软公司版权所有  1990年
计算机分销商展览
1990年秋  内华达州拉斯维加斯
欢迎来到1990年计算机分销商展览
太空摩托4
穆特尼
速打机
日本航空
万维网
唐娜·埃默森
Donna Emerson,
高级合伙人
senior partner.
我的天  这头衔真气派  是不是
My God, that does have a ring to it, doesn't it?
给
Here.
我本来喜欢红发妹的  但是天啊
You know I like redheads, but my God,
那新来的前台妹子真牛脾气
that new girl at reception got a real attitude.
-她逼你登记了吗  -可不是呢
- She make you sign in? - Well, she damn well did.
抱歉我错过了庆典
Hey, I'm sorry I missed the celebration.
圣胡安那边大风大雨的
We had a big storm down in the San Juans.
想不到你还是会欣赏万宝龙的人
I never pegged you for a Montblanc kind of guy.
其实没有  我就是挑了个包装好的
Well, I ain't. I thought it would go with the decor.
上面还有那朵小雪花
Also got that nice little snowflake thing right on top.
-多谢  博斯  -客气
- Thanks, Bos. - Sure.
我的天
Jeez.
你要不多待会儿
Hey, you wanna stick around?
下去喝杯咖啡什么的
Maybe got downstairs, get a cup of coffee, or--?
我倒是想  但是
Oh, I would love to, but, uh...
我还得赶路
I gotta hit the road.
黛安已经到葡萄园了
Diane's already up at the Vineyard.
总之
Look, anyway,
恭喜你
congrats.
话说  你去今年的计算机分销商展览吗
Oh, say. Are you going to Comdex this year?
去不了  我今年太忙了
Uh... no. Too much work this year.
现在都闹哄哄的  不像以前了
Oh, you know, it's a circus now. Not like it used to be.
费事不值得
It's more trouble than it's worth.
好吧
Well...
我可跟你说  那是好酒
All right. Hey, now, that's the good stuff.
别忘了  嗨就嗨翻天
Remember, respect the dirty bird
就怕玩闷的
or fear the kickin' chicken.
"玩闷的"
"Kickin' chicken"?
早安  雷
Morning, Ray.
安进可以  录进去
Amgen's a yes, put it on the tape.
这个我没兴趣  雷
Yeah, I'm not interested, Ray.
过
Pass.
这人目标大  收获小  雷
The guy's hunting elephants but bagging pigeons, Ray.
过
Pass.
过  雷
Pass, Ray.
你对泛林半导体怎么看
What's your position on Lam Research?
好吧  签限价单
All right, set up a limit order.
没兴趣  你知道我重视电信业
I'm not interested. You know I'm long on telecom.
就这样
That's all.
我们只是更希望
Look, we'd just prefer
能由你亲自来  哪怕只是一晚
if it was you coming out, even for one night.
两位  你们不用担心
Guys, you're in great hands.
伊莱亚斯会确保卡米诺电子在展会上大放光彩
Elias will make sure that CaminoWare is the talk of Comdex.
-等等  -而且等你们回到圣何塞
- Wait, wait, wait-- - And by the time you're back in San Jose,
我就已经准备好给你们B轮融资了
I'll have the table set for your Series B financing.
怎么样
How does that sound?
很好
All right.
那我们该去收拾了
Well, we should go pack.
对
Yeah.
对了
Yeah, yeah.
天啊  两位  你们的酒我请了
Oh, Jesus, guys, I've got your Heinekens.
回头到了展会上可别这么露怯
Whatever you do, don't do that at Comdex.
那好  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
实在是谢谢您了
It was really sweet of you.
唐娜  这块你是专家  你帮我论论理
Hey, Donna. This is your area of expertise. Settle a bet for me.
这哥们认为政府
This fellow thinks the feds
会在91年前放开对国家科学基金网的管制
are gonna deregulate all of NSFNET by '91.
戈登·克拉克  这位是
Gordon Clark, this here is--
唐娜  唐娜·埃默森
Donna. Donna Emerson.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
我刚说  就联邦政府那德性
Yeah, so I said the goddamn federal government
我订本《花花公子》
can't even deliver my Playboys
都隔三差五被不知哪个变态偷走
without some creep swiping them every other month.
最早也得93年了
'93 at the earliest.
有个田纳西州参议员
Well, there's a senator in Tennessee.
他在这事上很是执着
He's a real dog with a bone on this thing.
-看来你很自信嘛  -是的
- Oh, you seem really sure of yourself. - I am.
而且跟你说  长久以来  我也不自信
And you know, for a long time I wasn't.
然后突然间  我肩上的担子就减轻了
and then this... weight was suddenly lifted off of me.
什么样的担子啊
What kind of weight exactly?
就好像有人
Like someone poured cement
往保龄球里灌了水泥
in a bunch of bowling balls
然后把这些保龄球绑在了
and then strapped those bowling balls
一个胖杂技演员身上
onto a big fat circus man
然后这个演员爬上了一个梯子
and then he climbed this ladder...
-然后站在了你肩膀上  -你懂的
- And then stood on your shoulders? - You get it.
确实  我也才摆脱了自己的负担
I do! I cut loose a ball and chain of my own recently.
感觉无比解脱
Very liberating.
那现在呢  都是一夜情和大都市鸡尾酒了吗
So, what now? Just casual sex and cosmos?
一夜情和马蒂尼
Casual sex and martinis.
但是一夜情听起来太无聊懒散
Oh, but "Casual" makes it sound boring, lazy.
我觉得一夜激情更贴切点
I'd rather go with "Hot and dirty" sex.
说到这个  你今天有安排了吗
Speaking of, what are you doing later?
有约了  抱歉
Hot date, sorry.
我们的赌稍后再说吧
We'll settle the bet later.
再好不过
Yes, we will.
那是谁啊
Who was that?
不认识
I don't know.
那么  恭喜  正式定了
So, congratulations, it's official.
唐娜·埃默森
Donna Emerson.
你真是受不了克拉克这个名字  是吧
You really couldn't stand being a Clark, could you?
埃默森是三音节  有品味  懂吗
Emerson has three syllables. It's got stature, you know?
再说  在招牌上还能多占点地方
Plus, it takes up more space on the sign, so.
我的姓和你爸爸的姓  有区别吗
Well, my name, your dad's name-- what's the difference?
我们该走了
We should probably get a move on
要不就赶不上订的位置了  小戈
if we want to get our reservation, Gordo.
好  米歇尔  这是唐娜
Um, yeah. Uh, Michelle, this is Donna.
-唐娜  米歇尔  -就是这位啊
- Donna, this is Michelle. - Oh, of course.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
彼此彼此
You as well.
等我付了账就走好吗
Um, let me just close out my tab?
当然  我去拿衣服
Sure, yeah. I'm gonna grab my coat.
很高兴见到你
It was-- It was nice meeting you.
成小戈啦
Gordo?
埃默森女士
Ms. Emerson.
她看起来挺好的
She seems nice.
确实
She is.
周五你能照看一下琼妮吗
Hey, can you watch Joanie on Friday?
海莉还在太空夏令营呢
Haley's still at space camp and, you know,
琼妮就听听唱片  玩玩拼贴画
Joanie just listens to CDs and makes collages.
你也不用做什么
You really don't have to do anything.
黛安去了葡萄园
Look, Diane's at the Vineyard,
伊莱亚斯去了计算机分销商展览
Elias is at Comdex,
吉尔森也帮不上忙
Gilson's useless,
整个公司都由我负责
so, the whole company's on my shoulders.
我就是想问一下
I just thought I'd ask.
认了吧  轮到你了
Suck it up. It's your turn.
-喂  -乔
- Yeah? - Joe.
我是唐娜
It's Donna.
唐娜·克拉克
Donna Clark.
你好吗
How have you been?
你不该知道这个号码
You shouldn't have this number.
这样吧  我直说了
All right, look, I'll cut to the chase.
你会去计算机分销商展览吗
Are you going to Comdex?
有什么事吗  唐娜
What do you want, Donna?
卡梅伦会去
Cameron will be there.
我想给你发点东西
I want to send you something...
转交给她  一份备忘录
to give to her-- a memo.
你要我去展会
You want me to go to Comdex
给卡梅伦
to give Cameron...
一份备忘录
a memo?
你看看吧
Just read it.
如果你像我一样被打动
If it makes the same impression on you as it made on me,
你会乘最近一班飞机去维加斯
you'll be on the next plane to Vegas.
你那么迫切想联系上卡梅伦
If you want to get in touch with Cameron so bad,
为何不直接找她  却打给我
why are you calling me, not her?
你清楚原因
You know why.
乔  这次机会很适合她
Joe, this thing is perfect for her.
你...看看就明白了
Just... read it. You'll see.
我帮不了你  再见  唐娜
I can't help you. Good-bye, Donna.
豪伊兰顿太太
Mrs. Howe-Rendon?
我差点没认出你
I almost didn't recognize you.
我以为你会穿一件皮夹克
I expected you'd be wearing a leather jacket
还有好多文身
and have bunch of tattoos.
像《太空摩托》里那样
Like in Space Bike.
我们不一样
We're different people.
当然
Of course.
我带你过去
Let's get you set up.
他们就为这个
They fly you all the way
让你大老远从远东飞过来
out from the Orient just for this?
太牛了
Amazing.
就是这里
Here it is.
你好  我是特蕾西
Hi, I'm Tracy.
你好  特蕾西
Hi, Tracy.
他们叫我别坐在摩托上
They told me not to sit on the bike
因为我可能会坐坏它
because I might crush it.
他们说得对
That's probably good advice.
签售开始前
You've got a few minutes to settle in
你有几分钟准备一下
before the signing starts.
好啊
Oh, yeah.
这是你的午餐
Here's your lunch.
按照你的要求
As you requested,
加豆加奶酪的玉米煎饼
a bean and cheese burrito.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在日本待四年了
I've been in Japan for four years.
如果要我用一个词来形容自己的话
If I had to choose one word to describe myself,
我想我会说"探求者"
I guess I would say, um, "Seeker."
对  还有
Yeah, you know? And, uh...
"给予者"  是的
and "Giver." Yeah.
虽然我是个技术专家
I mean, I'm a tech professional
但我不仅仅只会编程
but I'm not just bits and bytes.
我拥有一家区域网络公司
I own a regional network
它是国家科学基金网的一部分
that's part of NSFNET,
基于Unix的路由  通过T1主干网
which connects researchers
让研究人员能与
to the National Science Foundation
国家科学基金会
super-computing center,
超级计算机中心相连
via T-1 backbone through a Unix-based rout--
这么说吧  我干得挺好的
Let's just say I do well for myself.
消遣对我来说很重要
Fun is very important to me,
如果随意的话
and listen, if, you know, it's casual,
如果保持随意的话  我可以接受
you know, it stays casual, I'm okay with that.
如果发展到稍正式一点的话
And if it becomes something more than casual
那我也可以接受
then I'm okay with that too. Yeah.
我喜欢露营  我真的很喜欢露营
And I like camping. I really like camping.
你喜欢露营吗
Do-- do you like camping?
最近  我开始学习烹饪  做饭
Recently, I've gotten into fine cuisine, uh, cooking.
真正的做饭
But, like, really doing it.
你可以做点什么
You get to cook something,
然后看着你做的东西
and then you look at it,
你会想"这是我做的"
and you think, "I made this!"
你把它吃了然后继续自己的生活
And then you get to eat it and then move on.
这让我很开心
That makes me happy.
我叫...我能看着镜头吗
My, uh, name-- Can I look into the thing?
-我叫戈登  -琼妮
- Uh, my name is Gordon... - Joanie?
编号108A-2
number 108A-2...
琼妮  这可是私人的东西
Joanie, that is private.
是啊  用一段录像向世人宣布
Yeah. Making a video that screams
"我需要上床"的确挺私人的
"I need to get laid" is totally private.
"上床"  谁教你的
"Get laid"? Who taught you that?
爸  学校有些孩子在停车场
Dad, I know kids in school giving handjobs
给人打飞机  我不是小孩子了
in the parking lot. I'm not a kid.
不  你不知道  是的  你是小孩子
No, you don't. And yes, you are.
好了  我什么时候送你去派对
All right. Now, what time am I taking you to this party?
-九点开始  -我能早点送你去吗
- It starts at 9:00. - Can I take you a little earlier?
我的女伴  好吧
My date-- Okay.
我要为一个人做晚饭  她七点半到
I'm cooking dinner for someone and she'll be here at 7:30.
可詹妮弗六点半要看《灵异入侵2》
Yeah, but Jennifer is seeing Child's Play 2 at 6:30
好跟踪博比·奥斯托夫
to go stalk Bobby Ostoff.
所以  她差不多八点半才能回来
So, she probably won't even be back until 8:30.
派对是在詹妮弗家吗
The party's at Jennifer's?
妈妈说我可以去
Mom said I could go.
你妈告诉我戴安这周都去出差
Yeah, well, Mom told me that Diane was out of town all week.
你不能去没有家长的派对
You can't go to a party if there aren't any parents there.
-你知道的  -可妈妈说我能去
- You know that. - But Mom said!
琼妮  你和我在一起的时候
Joanie, when you're staying with me,
-就由我说了算  -天啊
- I make the decisions. - God!
琼妮
Joanie?
谢谢
Thanks.
我为《太空摩托5》想了些绝妙的点子
Right, okay, so I've got some banging ideas for Space Bike 5.
有这么一条太空金鱼
Okay, so there's this-- there's this space goldfish--
好极了  那边付款
Fantastic! So, just pay over there.
你好  我叫杰西卡
Hi, I'm Jessica.
亚历克斯
Alex.
你俩回头去看雅达利演讲吗
You two going to the Atari keynote later?
-当然  -很好
- Yeah. - Good.
别让那样的男生在你们前面加塞
Don't let boys like that push their way in front of you.
-好的  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
能给"乔"签个名吗
Can you make it out to "Joe"?
那里的文化真是博大精深
Yeah, it's just a really amazing culture, you know?
你会说日语吗
Do you even speak Japanese?
这句话的意思是  "请把虾头去掉"
That means, "I don't want the shrimp with the heads on."
这句话在东京非常管用
It's a very useful phrase in Tokyo.
那你会留下来吗
So, you're gonna stay?
也许会吧
Maybe, yeah.
我不知道  我们真在那儿安顿下来了
It's-- I don't know, we've really settled in.
一开始很奇怪
It was weird at first.
就像外星人  你懂吗
Like, alien, you know?
《太空摩托2》的灵感就是这么来的
And that's what Space Bike 2 was all about.
就是  汤姆一直工作很忙
It was just, Tom was working a ton
而我在这座陌生的城市里闲逛
and I was wandering around this strange city
感觉迷茫  然后...
feeling lost. And then...
怎么说呢  有一天我突然决定要做这个
I don't know, one day I just decided to give myself over to it.
就这样  像有个开关
Just like that, like a-- like a switch...
在你脑中弹开了
flicked in your brain?
是啊
Yeah.
就是  你经历人生
It's just, you go through life
对自己是谁  自己做什么
and you have this idea of who you are,
有一定的看法  然后...
and what you do, and then...
突然发现不是那么回事
you discover it's total bullshit.
只是个防御机制
It's a defense mechanism,
一旦你停止维护自己  你就可以
and once you stop defending yourself you can be
成为别的  而那...
all these other things, and that...
-是啊  -很俗气吧
- Yeah. - seems totally cheesy.
不  并不
No, it's not.
我现在都用不好筷子
I still suck at using chopsticks.
那  你来这儿干什么
So, what are you doing here?
你还在做咨询吗
Are you still consulting?
我正考虑再做回那个
I'm thinking about getting back into that,
如果有好机会
if the gig is right.
这几年变化这么大  真不可思议
It's amazing how much changes in just a few years.
还有这么多没变
And how much stays the same.
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
我该去看看什么
What should I see?
你可以跳过所有的笔记本电脑
Well, you can skip all the laptops.
它们都是万变不离其宗
They're just variations on a theme.
微软的展位真是...
The Microsoft booth is "Ugh."
盖茨的演讲没那么好
Gates' speech is overrated.
去拿个抄本就行了
Just get the transcript.
飞利浦刚发布了一个可录音的CD
Oh, Phillips just released a recordable CD
Adobe新添了个PS软件还挺酷的
and Adobe added some cool stuff to this thing called Photoshop.
就这样...
So...
好吧
Yeah, great.
有意思
That's interesting.
是啊
Yeah.
天啊  真是
Well, God, it was--
见到你真好
it was great to see you,
我很开心
and, this was a lot of fun.
慢着  那是...
Wait. Are those...
83年那伙人吗
those guys from '83
他们的打印机特别差劲那个
that had that really terrible printer?
你跟他们说你是IBM的
You convinced them you were from IBM?
嗯  我们为了巨人买了他们的房间
Yeah. We bought out their suite for the Giant.
那个房间还赠送海鲜塔
That suite came with that free seafood tower.
你要干什么
what are you doing?
我们隆重推出  一体化兼容打印设备
Offering, fully-integrated TypeKit compatibility
高品质的散热器
while our superior heat sink
可以保证你们的...
ensures that your...
报告会不出岔子  而是一飞...
presentation won't drown, but rather, float...
冲天
Into the sky.
而且绝不会卡纸
Moreover, paper jams can scram...
这是难免的
That just happens.
你们可以稍作休息...
Meaning that you can sit back and relax....
享受一下数据的传送
And enjoy the flight-- the flight of your data, that is,
因为传输速度太快了
due to transfer speeds so fast
会让你觉得文件在...
that you'll think your documents were...
加油  小皮
Come on. Come on, Petey.
有点风  用手挡一下
There's a little breeze. Get your hand in front of it.
用手背试试
Use your backhand.
飞驰[着火了]
On fire.
不错  不错
Cool, cool, cool.
这是叫"S打印机"吗
So, it's called the, uh, the "S Printer"?
不  是"速打机"
Oh, no, ... "Sprinter."
-因为打印得非常快  -没有空格
- Because it prints really fast. - No space.
和火的比喻放一起有点混乱吧
It's kind of confusing with the flame gag, though.
这是混合隐喻
It's a mixed metaphor.
"S打印机"的确听起来更棒
"S Printer" does sound better, though.
-是吧  -没错  更严谨一些
- Doesn't it? - Yeah. It's got rigor behind it.
就好像研发部门对A到R型都不满意
Like the R&D Department was unsatisfied with models A through R,
到最后  经过大量努力...
and then finally, after a lot of sweat and tears...
我们自豪推出S版
We proudly bring you version S.
是速打机
It's the Sprinter.
没有空格
No space.
我认识你吗
Hey, do I know you?
拿个打火机吧  只能拿一个
Here, help yourself to a lighter. No, just one, please.
-你拿太多了  -祝你们好运
- Oh, that's a lot. - Good luck, guys.
-不能全部...  -她拿太多了
- Not all of-- - She took so many.
只能拿一个  谢谢  一个
Just one, please, one.
米歇尔
Michelle.
你穿的是什么  这...
What you got, what's--
那是
Oh, it,
写的是"亲亲厨师"  不过是二进制码
it says "Kiss the cook", but in binary code.
那么
So.
好吧
Oh. Well.
闻起来真香
It smells great.
是意大利肉酱
That's the Bolognese.
很多人以为面条起源于意大利
You know, a lot of people think that pasta's Italian,
其实是起源于中国
but it actually originated in China.
没错  公元前1100年
Yeah, 1100 B.C.
你要送我去派对  我给妈妈留言了
You're taking me to the party. I left a message on Mom's service.
-她会告诉你让我去  -琼妮
- She's gonna tell you to let me go. - Joanie?
这是米歇尔
This is Michelle.
米歇尔  这是我可爱的女儿  琼妮
Michelle, this is my lovely daughter, Joanie.
你好
Hello.
我喜欢你的上衣
I, -- I like your shirt.
看起来...很有内涵
It's very... cultural.
你喜欢内涵的
Do you like culture?
是什么意思
What's it, say?
"少年"在日语中是男孩的意思
Well, "shonen" is Japanese for "boy."
意思是男孩的刀
So, it means "boy knife."
男孩的刀就是指丁丁
"Boy knife" means "dick."
你想来点红酒吗
Do you want some wine?
我想知道要到多高
I wonder how high you'd have to be up
才能吐口唾沫就能砸死个人
for your spit to actually kill someone.
看看我们有什么宝贝
Okay, let's see what we got.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
别了  显得你屁股很大
Oh, I wouldn't. They make your ass look big.
好吧
Oh, okay.
规则是这样的
Here are the rules.
四排打火机
Four rows of lighters.
轮到你时  只要是同一排的
When it's your turn, you can take as many
随便你拿走几个打火机
or as few as you want, as long as they're from the same row.
拿走最后一个打火机的人输
The person who ends up with the last lighter loses.
你想第一个来还是第二个来
You wanna go first or second?
真大胆
Bold.
楼下有什么吸引你的产品吗
Is there anything on the floor catch your eye?
没有  我觉得速打机是最棒的
No, I'm going whole hog on the Sprinter.
这些家伙掌握了时代的潮流
Those guys really have their finger on the pulse.
其实...
Actually it was...
我看花了眼
it was all pretty overwhelming.
如果你仔细看
You know, if you look closely,
那些笨蛋中还是有钻石的
there are some diamonds in those dorks.
你真希望我搭上谁吗
Would you really wish me on anyone?
你输了
You lose.
这次你先来
You go first this time.
我们合作的时候
Hey, I knew what I was doing,
我知道自己在干什么
you know, when we worked together.
穆特尼自己一头扎进深渊
And Mutiny took a nosedive all on its own,
都不需要你来搅和
didn't need you to screw that one up for us.
戈登
And Gordon,
会第一个承认是自己做的选择
would be the first to admit that he made his own bed.
是啊  但是...
Yeah, but...
但是莱恩  对吧
But Ryan, right?
是啊  汤姆和我...
Yeah, Tom and I were...
听说时正要去日本
leaving for Japan when we heard.
刚开始我...
At first I was...
很生气
angry.
气你
At you...
也气他
and at him.
还有我自己
And at myself...
因为还有好多话没和他说
for all these things I never said to him.
然后我意识到
Then I realized
没人能帮到他
there was nothing anyone could have done about it.
你和我都不行
Not you and not me.
-你不能确定  -你也是
- You don't know that. - Neither do you.
你没有那么大威力
You're not that powerful.
最终  我的愤怒
So, eventually, my anger
变成了悲伤
turned into sadness, and...
那没事的  那是健康的
that's fine, that's healthy.
悲伤吧
I mean, yes, be sad.
但是  别再责怪自己了
But Jesus, stop blaming yourself.
我赢了
I win.
也不是为了莱恩
This isn't about Ryan.
是...
It's...
我就是觉得你不该
I'm just saying I don't think you should...
让世界享受不到你的工作
deprive the world of what you do.
好吧
Okay.
我做什么
What is it that I do?
真正的改变
It's so hard...
是很难实现的
to bring about actual change.
真正的改变
Real change.
全世界
The whole world
都会阴谋阻止改变
conspires to stop that from happening.
但你能让人们聚在一起
But you bring people together.
你能...创造改变
You... create change.
我觉得那...
I think that that's...
非常棒
really great.
我有个
Hey, so I have this
不得不去的雅达利派对
Atari party that I have to go to
如果你愿意来  跟我一起喝醉
that would be so much more fun if you would come
就会好玩得多
and get drunk with me.
是让我替你挡住狂热粉丝吗
What, so I can fend off your groupies?
没错
Exactly.
我没穿合适的衣服
I'm not really dressed for that kind of thing.
好吧
Okay.
那...
Well...
好了
Okay.
这下行了
Now I'm ready.
未来一片光明啊
The future's so bright.
总之  该说重点了
Anyways, back to the important stuff.
知道大部分人为什么做不好意面吗
Do you know why most people screw up their pasta?
-来了  -水加的盐不够
- Here we go. - Not salting the water enough.
应该有海洋的味道
You know, it should taste like the ocean.
如果比例得当
You know, when properly portioned,
盐不会让食物太咸
salt will not make food taste salty,
而是增强已经存在的味道
but instead will enhance the flavors that are already present.
找我的  妈妈打来的
It's for me. It's my mom.
她是一家风投公司的合伙人
She's a partner at a VC firm
所以她有自己的留言服务
so she has her own messaging service.
妈妈
Mom?
琼妮  我收到你的留言了  怎么回事
Joanie, I got your voicemail. What's going on?
你说得好像第三次世界大战
You made it sound like World War III ...
-开始了  -爸不许我去参加派对
- from your message. - Yeah, Dad won't let me go to the party,
太过分了  你明明说我可以去的
which is bullshit because you explicitly told me I could go.
他肯定有原因的  亲爱的
I'm sure he has good reasons, Bug.
我根本没有理由该被困在这里
There is no good reason why I should be stuck here
跟超级大厨
making pasta from scratch
和不知哪来的女人一起从零做意面
with freaking Chef Boyardee and some random lady.
是那个米歇尔吗
Is it that Michelle woman?
没错  她是爸爸的员工
Bingo-rama. She works for Dad.
听着  你在爸爸家  就得听他的
Look, when you're at Dad's house, his word goes.
你知道规矩的
You know the rules.
-你不能跟他谈谈吗  -不行  我没时间
- Can you just talk to him? - No, I don't have time--
爸  妈妈想跟你谈谈
Dad! Mom wants to talk to you.
你几年级了
So, what grade are you in?
我马上就要走了
You know, I'm gonna, like, go in a second.
你不用非得跟我说话
You don't have to talk to me anymore.
唐娜  我现在不想谈这个
Donna, I don't wanna have this conversation right now.
-我也不想  -她想去詹妮弗家
- Neither do I. - She wants to go over to Jennifer's
但是那里根本不会有家长
and there's not gonna be any parents there.
我已经跟她说她得听你的
I already told her that she has to listen to you.
她让你接电话  是以为我们能大吵一架
She just put you on the phone because she thought we'd fight
让她渔翁得利
and she'd come out on top.
你什么时候还做意面了
Since when do you make pasta?
我...
Oh, well, I-I--
我上了烹饪课
I took a cooking class.
我父母也在我小时候离婚了
My parents got divorced when I was little, too,
所以  我知道滋味不好受
so, I know it stinks.
但会好起来的
But it gets better.
好吧  你别想去了
All right, you're, uh, you're not going.
就算保守估计声音辨识部件的
So, even with a conservative estimate of the licensing fees
授权金
for the voice-recognition component,
三季度结束时
we'll be in three million
我们的产品也能进入三百万台家用电冰箱
domestic refrigerator-freezers by the end of Q3.
第四季度就能盈利了
And I'll hit profitability by Q4.
你们做什么的
So, what is it you do?
-我觉得就是他了  -我也觉得
- I think this is definitely him. - I think it's him!
听着  我们在此授予你...
Listen, man, we hereby confer upon you--
鲍勃
Uh, Bob.
Bob!
90年计算机分销商展览的最高荣誉
...the greatest honor of Comdex '90:
派对点子大师
the Party Pitch Swami
以及凡间无趣终结者
and a Vanquisher of Earthly Tedium.
我们自豪地赠与你
And we proudly present to you...
这个
This...
百分百合成的
100% synthetic
人体工学设计  获职业安全与健康管理局认可的
ergonomically designed OSHA-approved
思科腕垫
Cisco wrist rest.
过上梦想的生活吧  鲍勃
Live the life of your words, Bob.
要续杯吗
You want a refill?
好
Yeah!
老天爷  我的续杯都想续杯
Jesus, my refills want refills!
我超爱《太空摩托》
I love Space Bike!
我爱你
I love you!
卡梅伦
Cameron?
Cameron!
你好吗  日本好吗
How are you? How's Japan?
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我就是...
You know, I just...
来派对上转转
came to make an appearance at the parties, and...
好吧
Okay--
我
Look, I--
是来见你的
I came to see you.
你为什么要那么做
I don't know why you would do that.
因为我有...
Well, because I've got this--
有样东西
There's this thing.
非常棒  我想跟你分享
It's really exciting and I want to show it to you.
-你开玩笑呢  -求你
- You've got to be kidding. - Please, just--
别这样  明天跟我吃午饭吧
Come on, have lunch with me tomorrow.
不  我要飞早班机去东京
No, I'm on an early flight out to Tokyo.
都四年了  我们得...
It's been four years, we need to--
我们不用做什么
We don't need to do anything!
我们都做过我们不以为傲的事
We both did things we're not proud of,
如果能让时间倒流
and if could turn back the clock,
我们肯定不会那么做的
I'm sure we'd do it differently.
真是难以置信
I can't believe this is happening.
难道你就完全放下过去了吗
What, you're gonna tell me that you've completely moved on?
没有
No.
我每天都会想你和我
I think about you and me every day.
那让我非常生气
And it makes me furious.
那我们想办法和好  我想弥补
So, let's fix it. I wanna fix it.
我不想
I don't.
你还好吗
Everything okay?
我们走吧
Let's go.
帕玛森干酪
Parmigiano-Reggiano?
好的  谢谢
Yes, please.
我是素食主义者
I'm a vegetarian.
是吗  什么时候开始的
Oh, yeah? Since when?
自从我开始关注那些与我们
Since I started paying attention to the thinking,
共处在一个星球上的有思想的生灵
feeling creatures we share the planet with,
并且意识到他们可能不想被吃
and realized they probably don't like being eaten.
就是从那时开始
That's since when.
那自己把你的那份洗掉吧
Well, you can rinse yours off.
太迟了  已经被玷污了
Too late. It's tainted.
味道真不错
This is really good.
谢谢
Grazie.
你放了什么
What did you put in this?
意大利肉酱
Ah, it's the Bolognese.
花了好久才做好  但是
It's taken a while to perfect, but--
你知道吗
Did you know
几乎所有在超市中买到的牛肉
that almost all beef you buy at the supermarket
都有大肠杆菌
tests positive for E. Coli?
因为牛被宰杀时会被砍头
Because cows, when they're slaughtered, are decapitated.
牛被砍头时
And when you decapitate a cow,
其内脏和胃里的东西
all the stuff in the intestines and the stomach
都会从脖子口喷涌而出  喷得一身
flies out through the neck hole, all over the body.
大肠杆菌只在粪便里有
And E. Coli is found only in excrement.
所以说
Basically...
你的意大利肉酱里有屎
there's shit in your Bolognese.
琼妮  我们在吃饭呢
Okay, Joanie, we are trying to eat.
我也是
So am I.
所以我们都得思考
And that's why we all need to think about the gross, and, like,
我们盘中食物所经历的非人道处理加工
inhumane process that we get all the stuff we consume on our plates.
你知道大部分
Well, did you know there's
牛奶里都有可检测到的奶牛尿吗
a detectable level of cow piss in most milk?
我能理解  我五岁时
You know, I understand. When I was five,
放弃吃鸡蛋一整年
I gave up eggs for a whole year
因为我以为打碎鸡蛋时
because I thought when you cracked the eggs,
就杀死了小鸡宝宝
that you were killing little baby chicks,
每次我爸做煎蛋饼
and every time my dad made an omelet
我都会泪流满面
I would just burst into tears
大哭几小时
and just cry for hours.
我14了  不是五岁
I'm 14, not five.
这是个阶段  会过去的
She'll grow out of it. It's a phase.
你觉得这只是个阶段
You think this is just a phase?
好吧  琼妮  要不你拿盘子去隔壁屋吃
Okay, Joanie, why don't you take your plate into the other room
我们明天再谈
and we'll talk about this tomorrow.
好啊
Fine.
真抱歉
I am so sorry.
不不  何必呢
No. No, no, no. Why? I mean,
我真的几乎尝不出你意面里的屎味儿
I honestly can barely taste the shit in your spaghetti.
对于我  友谊是...
Uh, for me, friendship is...
非常重要的  我...
is very important. I mean, I...
我不仅仅只会编程
It's not all bits and bytes for me.
我经常看电影
And I see a lot of movies
如果能有个特别的人
and it would just be nice to have someone special
跟我一起看  一起聊聊就太好了
to share that with or talk to about that stuff.
亲密  是好事
Intimacy, that's-- it's-- that's nice.
听着
So, listen, um.
我真的很抱歉
I-- I really am sorry.
我
I, um--
-我们办公室见  -好
- I'll see you at the office. - Okay.
琼妮
Joanie.
你刚刚那是做什么
What the hell was that?
你就该让我去派对
You should have just let me go the party.
琼妮  就算你不开心
Joanie, just because you are unhappy
不代表你可以把你的痛苦
does not mean that you can inflict your total misery
施加到其他人身上
onto everyone else.
你太明显了
You're so obvious!
什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
之前你为妈妈工作  如今米歇尔为你工作
You work for Mom and now Michelle works for you.
你可以找更好的
You could do better.
你找到过一次了
You already did once.
她真让人难以置信
Can you believe her?
她就好像埋伏了我
It's like she ambushed me.
她干吗非要和好
Why does she care so much about kissing and making up?
我们都不住在一个国家了
We don't even live in the same country anymore.
她打给了我
She called me.
几天前
A few days ago.
为什么
Why?
她要我找到你
She wanted me to find you...
向你展示一个什么点子
and bring you some idea.
你是为此而来的吗
That's why you're here?
不是
No.
我说她如果想跟你谈  就该自己来
I told her if she wanted to talk to you, she could do it herself.
我都不知道那个点子是什么
I don't even know what the idea was.
我没看  也不在乎
I didn't read it and I don't care.
别这样  卡梅
Come on, Cam.
你可以信任我
You can trust me.
天呐  太难喝了
God, that's terrible.
我好像想出来了
Hey, I think I figured it out.
你打不赢我
You can't beat me. It's--
这是个系统  你得数尼姆和
It's a system. You have to count in Nim sums.
是有窍门的
It's just a trick.
你
Why...
为什么来
are you here?
你知道
You know why.
不
Nope.
告诉我
Tell me.
你
You.
我来见你
I came to see you.
我们不该待在这上面
We shouldn't be up here.
已经晚了
It's getting late.
我明早还得早走
I have to leave early tomorrow.
今晚就到这儿吧
Maybe we should call it a night.
嗯
Yeah.
是啊  就到这儿吧
Yeah, we should call it a night.
坚持
Consistency.
这我敬佩
I can admire that.
天呐  我特讨厌斯莱特
God, I hate it when Slater does that
傻乎乎地转椅子
stupid turnaround thing with his chair.
是啊
I know.
我们都懂  你是酷酷的运动员
It's like, okay, we get it, you're the cool jock.
不是吧
Are you serious?
怎么了
What?
-你  -我不能只给自己一个标签
- You-- - I can't totally commit to a label.
人不是单一的
People aren't one thing.
是啊
Yeah.
你说得对
You're right.
好吧
All right.
今早很严重吗
Is it bad this morning?
不  没事
No, it's fine.
我就是有点僵硬
I'm just a little stiff.
洗个热水澡就行了
Nothing a hot shower won't fix.
真是荒唐
This is ridiculous.
我要逼你跟我换卧室
I'm making you switch bedrooms with me.
爬楼梯简直太傻了
Climbing these stairs is totally dumbass.
是啊  那对你肯定好处多多
Yeah. I'm sure that would work out great for you.
一张好床  大衣橱
Nice fancy bed, big closet...
其实我想要的是浴室
Oh, it's really the bathroom I'm after.
跟你合作
Working with you was...
是我这辈子最快乐的时光
the most fun I ever had in my life.
好吗
Okay?
卡梅
Oh, Cam.
我好几次都想打电话
I picked up the phone so many times.
但从未真打过  是吧
Never actually called, though. Did you?
但是...
Well...
我现在来了
I'm here now.
你看了吗
Did you even read it?
什么
What?
我发给乔的东西  那个点子
What I sent Joe. The idea.
他没拿给我看
He never even showed it to me.
是什么
What was it?